Are you good with your hands?
你动手能力强吗？
Many of us like to make things which we can use or give as gifts.
我们很多人都喜欢制作一些可以自用或是当作礼物赠送的物件。
Crafting is certainly a hobby that’s seen a resurgence, and those who pursue it claim getting creative improves their mood.
爱好手工制作的风潮再次兴起，而那些投身其中的人表示，发挥创造力能让心情变得更好。
The recent lockdowns caused by the Covid pandemic gave people time at home to try out new activities, which they’ve continued to enjoy.
最近由新冠疫情所引发的封锁，让人们有了居家时间去尝试新活动，而这些活动也被大家一直延续了下来。
Many turned to hobbies such as craft making as a way to soothe their work-from-home burnout.
许多人选择手工制作这类爱好来缓解居家办公带来的倦怠感。
Knitting, crocheting, pottery and painting are all crafts that have seen a revival, and many of them are being done by younger people.
编织、钩针、陶艺和绘画这些手工技艺都迎来了复兴，并且其中不少爱好者都是年轻人。
But even before the pandemic, people were turning to arts and crafts as an interesting pastime and even a way to make a bit of pocket money.
但其实在疫情之前，人们就已经将手工艺当作一种有趣的消遣方式，甚至是赚点零花钱的途径了。
Numerous websites, such as Etsy and Folksy, allowed people to sell their handmade goods.
像爱Etsy和Folksy这样的众多网站，都为人们售卖手工制品提供了平台。
Richard Sennett, author of the Craftsman, told the BBC that: “A lot of people are finding their day jobs pretty empty, whereas learning a craft provides a real satisfaction.
《匠人》一书的作者理查德·桑内特在接受BBC采访时表示：“很多人觉得自己的日常工作十分空虚，而学习一门手艺却能带来实实在在的满足感。
It’s a skill – things like carpentry and weaving are mentally and physically stimulating, and people get inherent pleasure out of that kind of work”.
这是一种技能——像木工和编织这类手艺，既能锻炼脑力，又能活动身体，人们能从这类劳作中获得一种内在的愉悦感。”
The internet has also been the place to turn to to buy craft kits which help you get started with your craft-making projects, such as candle making or macrame.
互联网也成了人们购买手工材料包的好去处，这些材料包能帮你开启各类手工项目，比如制作蜡烛或是编织挂毯。
But many people are enjoying designing and making things from scratch and are doing it just for pleasure or to occupy their minds – and there’s evidence that it’s good for us as well.
不过也有很多人喜欢从零开始设计和制作物件，他们做这些只是为了消遣，或是让自己有事可做——而且有证据表明，手工制作对我们自己也大有裨益。
According to research commissioned by BBC Arts, even the briefest time spent on a creative pastime such as painting, pottery or playing the piano, has an impact on our wellbeing and emotions.
英国广播公司艺术频道委托开展的一项研究显示，哪怕只是花很短的时间投入一项创意消遣活动，比如绘画、陶艺或是弹钢琴，都会对我们的身心健康和情绪状态产生积极影响。
The survey of around 50,000 people found being creative can help avoid stress, free up mind space and improve self-development, which helps build self-esteem.
这项涵盖约5万人的调查发现，发挥创造力有助于缓解压力、放空思绪、促进自我成长，而这些都能帮助提升自信心。
So, if you’re looking for the perfect tonic for your stressed-out life, maybe now’s the time to get creative.
所以，如果你正在为自己压力满满的生活寻找一剂良方，或许现在就是动手发挥创造力的好时机。